Guide to the Robert S. Platt Papers 1898-1980
University of Chicago Library
- Series IV: Writings
  - "Regionalism in World Order," 1943 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - "Resources and Economic Interests of the Bermudas" (Ph.D. dissertation, University of Chicago, 1920), correspondence (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - "Resources and Economic Interests of the Bermudas" (Ph.D. dissertation, University of Chicago, 1920), manuscript and abstract (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - "A Review of Regional Geography," 1957 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - "The Rise of Cultural Geography in America," 1952 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - "The Saarland, an International Borderland: Social Geography from Field Study of Nine Border Villages," 1961, correspondence, grant proposal, maps (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - "The Saarland, an International Borderland: Social Geography from Field Study of Nine Border Villages," 1961, manuscript and offprint (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - "Significance of the Location of Bermuda," 1921 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - "Six Farms in the Central Andes," 1932 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - "South Range, Keweenaw Copper Country: A Mining Pattern of Land Occupancy," 1932 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - "Statement by Two Geographers," 1959 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Suggestions Concerning Desirable Lines of Research in the Fields of Geology and Geography, Bastin, Dunbar, and Platt, eds. (1936) (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - "Summary Memorandum on the Bad River Indian Reservation, Based on Reports of Field Study," 1940 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - "Tentative Interpretation of Middle Tennessee," 1927 "Transportation in Inter-Regional Relations," 1949 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - "An Urban Field Study: Marquette, Michigan," 1931 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - "Wellington D. Jones," 1957 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - "What A Geographer Thinks About," 1961 "Where Do the Cultures Meet?" 1940 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - "Working on the Professor's Terms," 1952 Addresses and Lectures (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - "Around the World in 47 Years," 1962 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Writings, "The Bermuda Islands," 1920 "Blueprint for Hemisphere Defense," 1941 "Bordering on Geology," 1948 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Writings, "Boundary between Canada and U.S.," 1953 "Boundary Reconnaissance in Europe," 1954 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - "Can We Avoid Determinism?" 1947 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - "Chasing a European Boundary," 1954 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Clark Lectures, 1950 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Writings, "Comparative Religions," 1937 "Conflicting Territorial Claims in the Upper Amazon," 1937 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - "Contributions of Geographers in Latin American Studies," 1961 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - "Critical Spots in Latin America," 1939 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - "Destruction and Resettlement around Volcanoes," 1961 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Writings, "Development of Field Study, Theory, and Method," 1961 "Dutch-German Border," 1955 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Writings, "Economic Union for the Americas," 1940 "Experiences in Germany," 1951 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Writings, "Geographical Aspects of Paricutin Volcano," 1961 "The Geographical Region," 1957 "Geography of Airways," 1946 "Geography of Religion," 1961 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - "Glimpses of the Decades," 1954 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - "Goings-On in Field Work," 1958 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - "A Half Century of Geography and Geographers," 1963 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Writings, "Impressions of Africa," 1961 "Inter-American Transportation," 1941 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - "Introductory Field Study," 1951 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - "A Latin Americanist Looks at Africa," 1961 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Lectures in Brazil, 1947 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - "Life in a Chinese City," 1921 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Writings, "My Discovery of Palestine," 1927 "My Religious Exposure," 1954 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Writings, "Natural Boundaries?" 1951 "Nature of Research in Geography," 1951 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - "Palestine," [1925] (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Writings, "Patterns of World Transport, Airwise and Otherwise," 1945 "Perambulations of Recent Weeks," 1956 "Problems in Adjustment of Boundaries," 1958 "Problems in Cultural Geography; Plantations; Forms of Land Tenure in Latin America," 1940 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Writings, "Recent History of Boundary Study," 1951 "Remarks at the Dedication of the Ralph Brown Room" 1963 "Talk at Gamma Alpha Smoker," 1921 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Writings, "What is There to Be Coordinated, and How?" 1940 "What Do We Have in Washington? What Do We Want?" 1945 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Writings, "Where's Bunker Hill?" 1941 "World Air Routes," 1945 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Writings, Miscellaneous untitled lectures, 1917-1961 Book Reviews (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Authors A-M (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Authors N-Z (Box 11, Folder 19)
- Series V: Field Notes
  - Subseries 1: United States and Canada
    - 1916-1917 (Fox Valley, Illinois) (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - 1919 (Chicago to Washington, D.C.; New York; Massachusetts; Cassville, Illinois) (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - 1920 (Ohio; Kentucky; Indiana; Maine; Washington, D.C. to Boston; Wisconsin; Illinois; Arkansas) (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - 1921 (St. Lawrence Valley; French Lick, Indiana; Wisconsin; Chicago to Boston) (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - 1922 (Pittsburgh to Key West; Texas; Missouri; Arkansas; New York to Chicago) (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Field notes, 1923-1925, 1923 (Michigan) 1924 (New York; Pennsylvania; Ontario) 1925 (Illinois) (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - 1926 (Tennessee; Alabama; Florida; Wisconsin) (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - 1928 (Missouri, New Mexico; Michigan; Georgia; Florida) (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - 1929 (Michigan) (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - 1951 (Chicago; Wisconsin) (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - 1952 (Wisconsin) (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - 1956-1958 (Michigan) (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Subseries 2: Bermuda
    - March 1919 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - March 1919 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - September 1919 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - September-October 1919 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - October 1919 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Map of Soncy Estate, Pembroke (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 3: Latin America and Caribbean
    - Latin American Project; proposals, maps, and itineraries (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - 1922 (Venezuela) (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - 1922 (Cuba; Puerto Rico; Panama; Dominican Republic) (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - 1922 (Panama; Costa Rica; Guatemala) (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - 1922 (Honduras; Guatemala; Mexico) (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - 1923 (St. Thomas; Trinidad; Venezuela) (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - 1928 (Cuba; Mexico) (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - 1930 (Peru) (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - 1930 (Colombia; Chile; Argentina; Paraguay; Brazil) (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - 1933 (Colombia; Venezuela) (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - 1935 (Peru) (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - 1935 (Brazil) (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - 1936 (Mexico) (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - 1940 (Venezuela) (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - 1947 (Brazil; Paraguay) (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - 1948 (Peru; Argentina; Brazil) (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - 1948 (Peru; Argentina; Brazil) (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - 1952 (Bahamas) (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - 1958 (Mexico) (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous notes, undated (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 4: Europe and North Africa
    - 1959 (Mt. Vesuvius and Pompeii) (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - 1963 (Spain; Morocco) (Box 15, Folder 10)
- Series VI: Departmental and Teaching Materials
  - Subseries 1: University of Chicago Department of Geography
    - Administrative correspondence, 1949-1951 (includes Ernest Colwell, Robert M. Hutchins, and Walter A. Bartky) (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Intra-faculty correspondence, 1955 and undated (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Departmental course offerings, 1946-1949 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Conference and symposia, 1923, 1955-1957 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Chicago-Frankfurt Interuniversity Project, 1952 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Research project proposals, 1936, 1950-1952, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 2: University of Chicago Teaching Materials
    - Advice on teaching by Rollin D. Salisbury, 1919 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Instructor's reports, 1920-1957 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Required texts, 1924-1957 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Geography of North America (Geography 5), 1920-1923 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - The Elements of Geography (Geography 1), 1923 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Advanced Field Course (Geography 466), 1928, itinerary and anonymous journal of Mexican traverse (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Introductory Geography (Geography 101), 1931 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Army Specialized Training Program (ASTP), Sequence C, Central America, 1943 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Army Specialized Training Program (ASTP), Sequence C, Economic Geography, 1943 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Army Specialized Training Program (ASTP), Sequence C, Economic Geography, 1943 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Army Specialized Training Program (ASTP), Sequence C, Political Geography, 1943 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Army Specialized Training Program (ASTP), Sequence C, Political Geography, 1943 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Army Specialized Training Program (ASTP), Sequence C, Physical Science, 1943 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Army Specialized Training Program (ASTP), Sequence C, Premeteorology, 1943 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Latin America (Geography 247), 1950 and undated (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Geographic Thought (Geography 391), 1955-1957 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Geographic Thought (Geography 391), notes collected in 1963 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Geographic Thought (Geography 391), Richard Hartshorne, The Nature of Geography (1939), copy annotated by RSP (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Geographic Thought (Geography 391), Richard Hartshorne, Perspective on the Nature of Geography (1959), copy annotated by RSP (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Methodology (Geography 516), 1957 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Cultural geography, notes and research materials (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous course notes and syllabi Other Teaching Materials (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Yale in China, notes and class assignments, 1915 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Yale in China, notes on climate (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Yale in China, correspondence, 1917-1922 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Yale in China, "How It Strikes the Newcomer," by RSP; brochure, map of Changsha (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - 82nd Infantry, officers' training camp, 1918 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - 82nd Infantry, "The Western Front," by RSP, 1918 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - 82nd Infantry, lecture notes (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - 82nd Infantry, student maps (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - 82nd Infantry, correspondence, 1918-1923 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Navy Department, Bureau of Aeronautics, lectures, 1944 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Michigan State University, Visiting Professor, 1957 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Ohio State University, Mershon Visiting Professor, 1961 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - United States Educational Foundation in Pakistan, Fulbright Scholar, official correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - United States Educational Foundation in Pakistan, travel arrangements (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - United States Educational Foundation in Pakistan, correspondence with friends (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - United States Educational Foundation in Pakistan, Pakistan Field Geographers (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - United States Educational Foundation in Pakistan, University of Karachi (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - United States Educational Foundation in Pakistan, University of Dacca (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - United States Educational Foundation in Pakistan, notes and maps (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Indiana University, Visiting Professor, 1963 Miscellaneous Student Papers (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Ada V. Espenshade, "Three American Sub-Capitals," 1940 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Ann Larimore, "The Cultural Geography of St. Charles, Mo.: Housetypes," A.M. thesis, 1955 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Richard S. Thoman, "Chicago, a City of Dynamicity," undated Richard S. Thoman, "The Bourmet-Boursma Farm Units: A Cursory Appraisal," undated (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Don Edward Totten, "Patterns of Group Occupance in the Manitoba-North Dakota Border Area," A.M. thesis, 1950 (Box 19, Folder 15)
- Series VII: Great Lakes Field Courses
  - List of students participating in Field Geography (Geography 7), 1920-1923; Field Course in the Green Bay Region (Geography 7), 1924-1927; and Field Course in the Northern Lakes Region (Geography 366), 1929-1951 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - 1920 (Ellison Bay, Wisconsin), correspondence and notes (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - 1921 (Ellison Bay, Wisconsin), notices (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - 1922 (Ellison Bay, Wisconsin), correspondence, notes, map (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - 1923 (Ellison Bay, Wisconsin), correspondence (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - 1924 (Ellison Bay, Wisconsin), correspondence and field notes (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - 1926 (Crystal Falls, Michigan), notes and maps (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - 1927 (Republic, Michigan), correspondence, notes, maps (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - 1929 (Marquette, Michigan), correspondence and clipping (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - 1930 (Marquette, Michigan), correspondence (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - 1931 (Houghton, Michigan), correspondence and clipping (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - 1932 (Sault Ste. Marie, Michigan), correspondence and notes (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - 1932 (Sault Ste. Marie, Michigan), student field reports (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - 1932 (Sault Ste. Marie, Michigan), student field reports (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - 1932 (Sault Ste. Marie, Michigan), student field reports (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - 1932 (Sault Ste. Marie, Michigan), printed maps and surveys (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - 1932 (Sault Ste. Marie, Michigan), student maps (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - 1932 (Sault Ste. Marie, Michigan), student research papers (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - 1932 (Sault Ste. Marie, Michigan), student research papers (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - 1933 (Phelps, Wisconsin), notes and student research paper (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - 1934 (St. Ignace, Michigan), notes and student research papers (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - 1935 (Ontonagon, Michigan), prospectus (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - 1938 (Newberry, Michigan), notes (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - 1939 (Iron Mt., Michigan), notes (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - 1940 (Ashland, Wisconsin), correspondence, notes, and clipping (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - 1940 (Ashland, Wisconsin), student research paper (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - 1942 (Showano, Minnesota), notes (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - 1946 (International Falls, Minnesota), correspondence, notes, clippings (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - 1946 (International Falls, Minnesota), student field reports (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - 1946 (International Falls, Minnesota), student field reports (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - 1946 (International Falls, Minnesota), student maps (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - 1946 (International Falls, Minnesota), student maps (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - 1946 (International Falls, Minnesota), student research papers (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - 1946 (International Falls, Minnesota), student research papers (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - 1947 (St. Regis, Quebec), correspondence and notes (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - 1947 (St. Regis, Quebec), student field reports (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - 1947 (St. Regis, Quebec), student field reports (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - 1947 (St. Regis, Quebec), student field reports (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - 1947 (St. Regis, Quebec), student field reports (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - 1947 (St. Regis, Quebec), student maps (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - 1947 (St. Regis, Quebec), student research papers (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - 1947 (St. Regis, Quebec), student research papers (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - 1947 (St. Regis, Quebec), student research papers (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - 1948 (Emerson, Minnesota), correspondence and notes (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - 1948 (Emerson, Minnesota), student field reports (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - 1948 (Emerson, Minnesota), student field reports (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - 1948 (Emerson, Minnesota), student field reports (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - 1948 (Emerson, Minnesota), student maps (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - 1948 (Emerson, Minnesota), field reports student maps (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - 1948 (Emerson, Minnesota), field reports student maps (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - 1948 (Emerson, Minnesota), field reports student maps (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - 1948 (Emerson, Minnesota), field reports student maps (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - 1948 (Emerson, Minnesota), field reports student maps (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - 1949 (Ft. William, Ontario), notes (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - 1949 (Ft. William, Ontario), printed maps (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - 1949 (Ft. William, Ontario), student field reports (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - 1949 (Ft. William, Ontario), student maps Folder 7: 1949 (Ft. William, Ontario), student research papers (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - 1949 (Ft. William, Ontario), student research papers (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - 1949 (Ft. William, Ontario), student research papers (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - 1949 (Ft. William, Ontario), student research papers (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - 1949 (Ft. William, Ontario), student research papers (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - 1950 (Sault Ste. Marie, Michigan), notes (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - 1950 (Sault Ste. Marie, Michigan), student field reports (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - 1950 (Sault Ste. Marie, Michigan), student maps (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - 1950 (Sault Ste. Marie, Michigan), student research papers (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - 1950 (Sault Ste. Marie, Michigan), student research papers (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - 1950 (Sault Ste. Marie, Michigan), student research papers (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - 1951 (Niagara Falls, Ontario), notes (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - 1951 (Niagara Falls, Ontario), student field reports (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - 1951 (Niagara Falls, Ontario), student maps (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - 1951 (Niagara Falls, Ontario), student research papers (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - 1951 (Niagara Falls, Ontario), student research papers (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - 1951 (Niagara Falls, Ontario), student research papers (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - 1951 (Niagara Falls, Ontario), student research papers (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - 1951 (Niagara Falls, Ontario), student research papers (Box 26, Folder 8)
- Series VIII: Annals of the Association of American Geographers
  - Subseries 1: General Correspondence
    - Allen Press (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Association of American Geographers, Central Office (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Association of American Geographers, Central Office (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Broek, Jan O. M. (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Chorley, R.J. (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Gerlach, Arch C. (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Ginsburg, Norton (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Harrison, Richard Edes (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Kikolski, Bohdan (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Kniffen, Fred (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Kollmorgen, Walter (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Lewthwaite, Gordon R. (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Mikesell, Marvin W. (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Moodie, Arthur E. (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - Pounds, Norman J.G. (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Roder, Wolf (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Ruhe, Robert V. (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Rutherford, John (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Sopher, David E. (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Spencer, Joseph E. (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Wheeler, Jesse (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Others, A-F (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Others, G-J (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Others, K-N (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - Others, P-Y (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Subseries 2: Correspondence Regarding Published Articles
    - March 1961 (Vol. 51, No. 1) (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - June 1961 (Vol. 51, No. 2) (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - September 1961 (Vol. 51, No. 3) (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - December 1961 (Vol. 51, No. 4) (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - March 1962 (Vol. 52, No. 1) (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - June 1962 (Vol. 52, No. 2) (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - September 1962 (Vol. 52, No. 3) (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - March 1963 (Vol. 53, No. 1) (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - March 1963 (Vol. 53, No. 1) (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - June 1963 (Vol. 53, No. 2) (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - September 1963 (Vol. 53, No. 3) (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - September 1963 (Vol. 53, No. 3) (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - December 1963 (Vol. 53, No. 4) (Box 29, Folder 11)
- Series IX: Postcards
  - Bermuda (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Latin America (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Latin America (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Great Lakes (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Great Lakes (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Southern United States (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Caribbean (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Caribbean (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Dutch-German Border (Box 30, Folder 9)
- Series X: Photographs
  - Subseries 1: Negatives
    - Hotchkiss School, 1910 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Yale University, 1910-1912 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Japan and China, 1913 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Yale University, 1913-1914; Norway and Sweden, 1914 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - China, 1914-1915 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - J. Paul Goode field trip to western U.S., 1915 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - University of Chicago, 1915-1916; military service, 1917-1918 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous negatives separated by RSP:China; U.S. Army; R.D. Salisbury field trip to Stony Island (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Ellison Bay, Wisconsin, 1920; Dept. of Geography picnic, 1920; Geography 7 field trip to Green Bay, 1921 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Geography 6 field trip in Chicago vicinity, 1922; Geography 7 field trip to Ellison Bay, 1922; field trip to Ellison Bay, Iron Mt., and Fox Valley, 1923 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Field trip to Dubuque, 1924; Ellison Bay, 1924; geographers' field conference, Sawyer, Michigan, 1929; Geography 366 field trip to Marquette, Michigan, 1929 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Geography 366 field trip to Sault Ste. Marie, Michigan, 1932; Dept. of Geography picnic, 1934 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 2: Prints
    - RSP and Platt family (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - University of Chicago campus views entered in photographic contest (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Dept. of Geography (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Latin America (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Latin America (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Latin America (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Latin America (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Latin America (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - Latin America (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Latin America (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Latin America, RSP and field party (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Great Lakes region (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Great Lakes region (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Great Lakes region (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Great Lakes field courses, RSP and students (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - German border (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - Saarland (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Subseries 3: Movie Film
    - RSP and students, 3 reels, 16mm (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Subseries 4: Glass Slides
    - China, 1914-1915 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Dept. of Geography and geographers' field conferences, 1914-1923 and undated (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - James Bay traverse, 1934 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 5: Film Slides
    - Section 1: 1898-1917 (Box 36)
    - Section 2: 1919-1920 (Box 36)
    - Section 3: 1921-1923 (Box 36)
    - Section 4: 1924-1929 (Box 36)
    - Section 5: 1930-1931 (Box 36)
    - Section 6: 1932-1935 (Box 36)
    - Section 7: 1936-1939 (Box 36)
    - Section 8: 1940-1947 (Box 36)
    - Section 9: 1948-1949 (Box 36)
    - Section 1: 1950-1951 (Box 37)
    - Section 2: 1952 (Box 37)
    - Section 3: 1953 (Box 37)
    - Section 4: 1954 (Box 37)
    - Section 5: 1955 (Box 37)
    - Section 6: 1956-1962 (Box 37)
    - Section 7: 10820 S. Drew, various events, 1925-1955 (Box 37)
    - Section 8: Portraits of RSP (Box 37)
- Series XI: Restricted
  - Instructor’s reports, 1936-1957 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence with students concerning theses, 1929-1942 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Letters of recommendation, 1932-1955 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Latin America (Geography 247), 1950 and undated (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Ada V. Espenshade, “Three American Sub-Capitals,” 1940 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Richard S. Thoman, “Chicago, a City of Dynamicity,” undated (Box 38, Folder 6)